ALBERT K. HOANG DUC

E: a.hoangduc@gmail.com • M: +1 416 788 4939 • Toronto, ON, Canada www.linkedin.com/in/alberthoangduc

Data Scientist / Ph.D. in Machine Learning

Enthusiastic professional with a passion for data science, analytics and machine learning looking for a Quantitative Research / Data Scientist position within the financial industry. Several years of experience in applying machine learning algorithms to solve real-world problems. Ability to manage all aspects of research process including methodology selection, data collection and analysis, testing, prototyping, back-testing, and performance monitoring.

Fluent in English and French. Core competencies:

Data Science ● Machine Learning ● Computer Programming

Education

University College London • London, UK • 2014

PhD in Machine Learning - Topic: Machine Learning in Medical Imaging

Ecole des Mines • Nantes, France • 2005 / 2003

MSc in Computer Science / BSc in Mathematics

Technical Skills

C++ • Matlab • Bash • Python (SciPy, SciKit) • Linux • Excel • LaTeX

Professional Experience

Idea Couture ◆ Toronto, Canada ◆ Jan. 2015 - present Contracting as Lead Data Scientist

Idea Couture is a strategy innovation firm based in Toronto, Canada

- Using mathematics, probabilistic models and machine learning algorithms to produce predictive insights from large structured and unstructured data set.
- Identifying and quantifying business opportunities from those insights and convert them into commercial services or products.
- Providing advice and recommendations to executive management using data analytics.

University College London ● London, UK ● Sept. 2010 – Nov. 2014 Doctoral researcher

- Designed and implemented innovative data analysis algorithms and tools for the detection of tumor in medical images.
- Processed and analyzed large volume of medical data to detect disease patterns.
- Developed fast and accurate computer diagnosis tools based on machine learning to be used in clinical practice.
- Investigated various analysis techniques and applied them to the field of medical image computing.
- Published 2 research papers as main author.

University of California ● Berkeley, CA, USA ● Oct. 2007 – Oct. 2009 Research Fellow

- Developed new software applications and maintained existing ones.
- Produced supporting documents, detailed specifications, test scenarios and reports.
- Served as main contact for end-user support.
- Responded to user problems in a timely manner.
- Provided technical solutions to other duties assigned by management.
- Published 1 research paper as main author.